Finding Aid for First Presbyterian Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.) records, 1872-1972
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
First Presbyterian Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.) records 1872-1972
First Presbyterian Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.).
2.5 linear feet, 1 oversize folder, and 2 microfilm rolls
86799 Ba 2; UBAm; Ba Microcopy
Presbyterian church established in Ann Arbor, Michigan in 1826; session minutes, correspondence, miscellaneous other record books.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The bulk of the records came from the church (donor no. 3602 ); other materials came from the Presbyterian Corporation (donor no. 1763 ) and the Presbyterian Campus Center (donor no. 3660 )
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The First Presbyterian Church of Ann Arbor was established in 1826.
The record group consists of session minutes, 1872-1972; records of University of Michigan student organization named the Presbyterian Corporation of the University of Michigan (formerly the Tappan Presbyterian Hall Association); records of other church groups, including the First Presbyterian Society, the Christian Endeavor Society, the Women's Foreign Missionary Society and the Westminster Guild; and photographs.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); United Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A.--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Presbyterian Corporation of the University of Michigan.; University of Michigan--Religion.; Women--Michigan--Ann Arbor--Societies and clubs.; Youth--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Women--Religious life--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Youth--Religious life--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Churches.; Churches--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; First Presbyterian Church (Ann Arbor, Mich.); Presbyterian churches--Michigan--Ann Arbor.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Session minutes, 1872-1972
  - May 3, 1872-January 8, 1957 (Reel 1)
  - January 31, 1957-January 13, 1972 (Reel 2)
- Correspondence and other papers
  - Historical sketch, undated (Box 1)
  - Papers, undated, 1887-1895 and 1903-June 1929, 17 folders (Box 1)
  - July 1929-1959, 24 folders (Box 2)
- Church organizations
  - Minute book of the First Presbyterian Society, 1883-1908 (Box 2)
  - Secretary's Record of the Women's Foreign Missionary Society, 1915-1926 (Box 2)
  - Christian Endeavor Society records, 1897-1910 (Box 2)
  - Presbyterian Corporation of the University of Michigan (formerly the Tappan Presbyterian Hall Association)
    - Minute book, 1890-1917 (TPHA) (Box 3)
    - Minute book, 1917-1923 (TPHA) (Box 3)
    - Records, 1922-1933 (UMPC) (Box 3)
  - Westminster Guild records, 1949-1953 (Box 3)
- Photographs
  - Photographs of exterior of church buildings and miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Church personalities (Folder UBAm)